In this video, I'd like to tell you about the idea of vectorization.
在这段视频中 我将介绍有关向量化的内容
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
So, whether you're using Octave
无论你是用Octave
or a similar language like MATLAB
还是别的语言 比如MATLAB
or whether you're using Python
或者你正在用Python
and NumPy or Java CC++.
NumPy 或 Java C C++
All of these languages have either
所有这些语言都具有
built into them or have
各种线性代数库
readily and easily accessible, different
这些库文件都是内置的
numerical linear algebra libraries.
容易阅读和获取
They're usually very well written,
他们通常写得很好
highly optimized, often so that developed by
已经经过高度优化
people that, you know, have PhDs in numerical computing or
通常是数值计算方面的博士
they are really specializing numerical computing.
或者专业人士开发的
And when you're implementing machine
而当你实现机器学习算法时
learning algorithms, if you're able
如果你能
to take advantage of these
好好利用这些
linear algebra libraries or these
线性代数库或者说
numerical linear algebra libraries and
数值线性代数库
mix the routine calls to them
并联合调用它们
rather than sort of right call
而不是自己去做那些
yourself to do things that these libraries could be doing.
函数库可以做的事情
If you do that then
如果是这样的话 那么
often you get that "first is more efficient".
通常你会发现 首先 这样更有效
So, just run more quickly and
也就是说运行速度更快
take better advantage of
并且更好地利用
any parallel hardware your computer
你的计算机里可能有的一些并行硬件系统
may have and so on.
等等
And second, it also means
第二 这也意味着
that you end up with less code that you need to write.
你可以用更少的代码来实现你需要的功能
So have a simpler implementation
因此 实现的方式更简单
that is, therefore, maybe also more likely to be bug free.
代码出现问题的有可能性也就越小
And as a concrete example.
举个具体的例子
Rather than writing code
与其自己写代码
yourself to multiply matrices, if
做矩阵乘法
you let Octave do it by
如果你只在Octave中
typing a times b,
输入 a乘以b
that will use a very efficient
就是一个非常有效的
routine to multiply the 2 matrices.
两个矩阵相乘的程序
And there's a bunch of examples like
有很多例子可以说明
these where you use appropriate vectorized implementations.
如果你用合适的向量化方法来实现
You get much simpler code, and much more efficient code.
你就会有一个简单得多 也有效得多的代码
Let's look at some examples.
让我们来看一些例子
Here's a usual hypothesis of linear
这是一个常见的线性回归假设函数
regression and if you
如果
want to compute H of
你想要计算 h(x)
X, notice that there is a sum on the right.
注意到右边是求和
And so one thing you could
那么你可以
do is compute the sum
自己计算
from J equals 0 to J equals N yourself.
j =0 到 j = n 的和
Another way to think of this
但换另一种方式来想想
is to think of h
是把 h 看作
of x as theta transpose x
θ 转置乘以 x
and what you can do is
那么
think of this as you know, computing this
你就可以写成
in a product between 2 vectors
两个向量的内积
where theta is, you know, your
其中 θ 就是
vector say theta 0, theta 1,
θ0  θ1
theta 2 if you have 2 features.
θ2 如果你有两个特征量
If n equals 2 and if
如果 n 等于2 并且如果
you think of x as this
你把 x 看作
vector, x0, x1, x2
x0 x1 x2
and these 2 views can
这两种思考角度
give you 2 different implementations.
会给你两种不同的实现方式
Here's what I mean.
比如说
Here's an unvectorized implementation for
这是未向量化的代码实现方式
how to compute h of
计算 h(x) 是未向量化的
x and by unvectorized I mean, without vectorization.
我的意思是 没有被向量化
We might first initialize, you know, prediction to be 0.0.
我们可能首先要初始化变量 prediction 的值为0.0
This is going to eventually, the
而这个
prediction is going to be
变量 prediction 的最终结果就是
h of x and then
h(x) 然后
I'm going to have a for loop for
我要用一个 for 循环
j equals one through n+1
j 取值 0 到 n+1
prediction gets incremented by
变量prediction 每次就通过
theta j times xj.
自身加上 θ(j) 乘以 x(j) 更新值
So, it's kind of this expression over here.
这个就是算法的代码实现
By the way, I should mention in these
顺便我要提醒一下
vectors right over here, I
这里的向量
had these vectors being 0 index.
我用的下标是 0
So, I had theta 0 theta 1,
所以我有 θ0 θ1
theta 2, but because MATLAB
θ2 但因为 MATLAB
is one index, theta 0
的下标从1开始 在 MATLAB 中 θ0
in MATLAB, we might
我们可能会
end up representing as theta
用 θ1 来表示
1 and this second element
这第二个元素
ends up as theta
最后就会变成
2 and this third element
θ2 而第三个元素
may end up as theta
最终可能就用
3 just because vectors in
θ3 表示 因为
MATLAB are indexed starting
MATLAB 中的下标从1开始
from 1 even though our real
即使我们实际的
theta and x here starting,
θ 和 x 的下标从0开始
indexing from 0, which
这就是为什么
is why here I have a for loop
这里我的 for 循环
j goes from 1 through n+1
j 取值从 1 直到 n+1
rather than j go through
而不是
0 up to n, right? But
从 0 到 n 清楚了吗？
so, this is an
但这是一个
unvectorized implementation in that we
未向量化的代码实现方式
have a for loop that summing up
我们用一个 for 循环
the n elements of the sum.
对 n 个元素进行加和
In contrast, here's how you
作为比较 接下来是
write a vectorized implementation which
向量化的代码实现
is that you would think
你把
of x and theta
x 和 θ
as vectors, and you just set
看做向量 而你只需要
prediction equals theta transpose
令变量 prediction 等于 θ转置
times x. You're just computing like so.
乘以 x 你就可以这样计算
Instead of writing all these
与其写所有这些
lines of code with the for loop,
for 循环的代码
you instead have one line
你只需要一行代码
of code and what this
这行代码
line of code on the right
右边所做的
will do is it use
就是
Octaves highly optimized numerical
利用 Octave 的高度优化的数值
linear algebra routines to compute
线性代数算法来计算
this inner product between the
两个向量的内积
two vectors, theta and X. And not
θ 以及 x
only is the vectorized implementation
这样向量化的实现不仅仅是更简单
simpler, it will also run more efficiently.
它运行起来也将更加高效
So, that was Octave, but
这就是 Octave 所做的
issue of vectorization applies to
而向量化的方法
other programming languages as well.
在其他编程语言中同样可以实现
Let's look at an example in C++.
让我们来看一个 C++ 的例子
Here's what an unvectorized implementation might look like.
这就是未向量化的代码实现可能看起来的样子
We again initialize prediction, you know, to
我们再次初始化变量 prediction 为 0.0
0.0 and then we now have a full
然后我们现在有一个完整的
loop for J0 up to
从 j 等于 0 直到 n
n.  Prediction + equals
变量 prediction +=
theta j times x j where
theta[j] 乘以 x[j]
again, you have this x + for loop that you write yourself.
再一次 你有这样的自己写的 for 循环
In contrast, using a good
与此相反 使用一个比较好的
numerical linear algebra library in
C++ 数值线性代数库
C++, you could use
你就可以用这个方程
write the function like or rather.
In contrast, using a good
与此相反 使用较好的
numerical linear algebra library in
C++ 数值线性代数库
C++, you can instead
你可以写出这样的代码
write code that might look like this.
So, depending on the details
因此取决于你的
of your numerical linear algebra
数值线性代数库的内容
library, you might be
你可以有一个
able to have an object that
is a C++ object which is
C++ 对象
vector theta and a C++
theta 和一个 C++
object which is a vector X,
对象 向量 x
and you just take theta dot
你只需要用 theta.transpose ()
transpose times x where
乘以 x
this times becomes C++ to
而这次是让 C++ 来实现运算
overload the operator so
因此
that you can just multiply these two vectors in C++.
你只需要在 C++ 中将两个向量相乘
And depending on, you know,  the details
根据
of your numerical and linear algebra
你所使用的数值和线性代数库的使用细节的不同
library, you might end
你最终使的代码表达方式
up using a slightly different and
可能会有些许不同
syntax, but by relying
但是通过
on a library to do this in a product.
一个库来做内积
You can get a much simpler piece
你可以得到一段更简单
of code and a much more efficient one.
更有效的代码
Let's now look at a more sophisticated example.
现在 让我们来看一个更为复杂的例子
Just to remind you here's our
提醒一下
update rule for gradient descent
这是线性回归算法梯度下降的更新规则
for linear regression and so,
所以
we update theta j using this
我们用这条规则对 j 等于 0 1 2 等等的所有值
rule for all values of J equals 0, 1, 2, and so on.
更新 对象 θ j
And if I just write
我只是
out these equations for
用 θ0 θ1 θ2 来写方程
theta 0 Theta one, theta two.
Assuming we have two features.
那就是假设我们有两个特征量
So N equals 2.
所以 n等于2
Then these are the updates we
这些都是我们需要对
perform to theta zero, theta one, theta two.
theta0 theta1 theta2的更新
where you might remember my
你可能还记得
saying in an earlier video
在以前的视频中说过
that these should be simultaneous updates.
这些都应该是同步更新
So let's see if
因此 让我们来看看
we can come up with a
我们是否可以拿出一个
vectorized implementation of this.
向量化的代码实现
Here are my same 3 equations written
这里是和之前相同的三个方程
on a slightly smaller font and you
只不过用更小一些的字体写出来
can imagine that 1 wait
你可以想象
to implement this three lines
实现这三个方程的方式之一
of code is to have a
就是用
for loop that says, you
一个 for 循环
know, for j equals 0,
就是让 j 等于0
1 through 2 the update
1 2
theta J or something like that.
来更新 θ j
But instead, let's come up
但让我们
with a vectorized implementation and see if we can have a simpler way.
用向量化的方式来实现 并看看我们是否能够有一个更简单的方法
So, basically compress these three
基本上用三行代码
lines of code or a
或者一个 for 循环
for loop that, you know, effectively does these 3 sets, 1 set at a time.
一次实现这三个方程
Let's see who can these 3
让我们来看看谁能用这三步
steps and compress them into
并将它们压缩成
1 line of vectorized code.
一行向量化的代码
Here's the idea.
这个想法是
What I'm going to do is I'm
我打算
going to think of theta
把 θ 看做一个向量
as a vector and I'm
然后我用
going to update theta as theta
θ 减去
minus alpha times some
α 乘以 某个别的向量
other vector, delta, where
δ 来更新 θ
delta is going to be
这里的 δ 等于 m 分之 1
equal to 1 over
m, sum from I equals
i=1 到 m 加和
one through m and then
this term on the
然后这个表达式
right, okay?
好吗?
So, let me explain what's going on here.
让我解释一下是怎么回事
Here, I'm going to treat
在这里 我要把
theta as a vector
θ 看作一个向量
so, there's an N+1 dimensional vector.
有一个 n+1 维向量
I'm saying that theta gets, you know, updated
我是说 θ 被更新
as--that's the vector, our N+1.
我们的 n+1 维向量
Alpha is a real
α 是一个实数
number and delta
δ
here is a vector.
在这里是一个向量
So, this subtraction operation, that's a vector subtraction.
所以这个减法运算是一个向量减法
Okay?
清楚吗 ?
Because alpha times delta
因为 α 乘以 δ
is a vector and so
是一个向量 所以
I'm saying if theta gets, you know, this
θ 就是 θ 减去 α 乘以 δ 得到的向量
vector, alpha times delta subtracted from it.
So, what is the vector delta?
那么什么是向量 δ 呢 ?
Well, this vector delta looks like this.
嗯 向量 δ 是这样子的
And what this meant to
这实际上代表的是
be is really meant to be
this thing over here.
这部分内容
Concretely, delta will be
具体地说 δ 将成为
a N+1 dimensional vector and
n +1 维向量
the very first element of
并且向量的第一个元素
the vector delta is going to be equal to that.
就等于这个
So, if we have
所以我们的 δ
the delta, you know, if we index it
如果要写下标的话
from 0--this is delta 0, delta 1, delta 2.
就是从零开始 δ0 δ1 δ2
What I want is that
我想要的是
delta 0 is equal
δ0 等于
to, you know, this
这个
first box also green up
第一行绿色框起来的部分
above and indeed, you might
事实上 你可能会
be able to convince yourself that delta
写出 δ0 是
0 is this 1 of m,
m 分之 1
sum of, you know, h of
h(x) 减去 y(i)
x.   xi minus
乘以 x(i)0 的和
yi times xi0.
So, let's just make
所以让我们
sure that we're on the
在同一页上
same page about how delta really is computed.
计算真正的 δ
Delta is one of m
δ 就是 m 分之 1
times the sum over here
乘以这个和
and, you know, what is this sum?
那这个和是什么 ?
Well, this term over
恩 这个符号
here, that's a real number.
是一个实数
And the second term over here, xi.
这里的第二个符号 是 x(i)
This term over there is a
这个符号是一个向量
vector, right? Because xi might
对吧 ? 因为 x(i)
be a vector.
可能是一个向量
That would be
这将是
xi0, xi1, xi2 right?
x(i)0 x(i)1 x(i)2 对吧 ?
And what is the summation?
那这个求和是什么 ?
Well, what does summation say
恩 这个求和就是
is that this term
这里的式子
over here.
就在这里
This is equal to h+x1-y1 times
等于 h(x(1)) - y(1) 乘以 x(1)
x1 + h of
加上
x2-y2 times x2
h(x(2)) - y(2) 乘以 x(2)
+ you know, and so on.
依此类推
Okay?
对吧 ?
Because this is a summation of
因为这是对 i 的加和
the I. So, as I
所以
ranges from I1 through m,
当 i 从 1 到 m
you get these different terms and you're summing up these terms.
你就会得到这些不同的式子 然后作加和
And the meaning of each of these
每个式子的意思
terms is a lot like
很像
- if you remember actually from
如果你还记得实际上
the earlier quiz in this, if you solve this equation.
在以前的一个小测验 如果你要解这个方程
We said that in order to
我们说过
vectorize this code, we
为了向量化这段代码
will instead set u2v+5w. So,
我们会令 u = 2v +5w 因此
we're saying that the vector u
我们说 向量u
is equal to 2 times
等于2乘以向量v
the vector v plus 5 times
加上 5乘以向量 w
the vector w. So, just an
用这个例子说明
example of how to
如何对不同的向量进行相加
add different vectors and this summation is the same thing.
这里的求和是同样的道理
It's a saying that this
这一部分
summation over here is just some real number right?
只是一个实数
That's kind of like the number
就有点像数字 2
2 and some other number
而这里是别的一些数字
times the vector x1.
来乘以向量x1
This is like 2 times v instead
这就像是 2v
with some other number times x1
只不过用别的数字乘以 x1
and then plus, you know, instead of
然后加上 你知道
5xw, we instead have some
不是5w 而是用
other real number plus some
别的实数乘以
other vector and then you
一个别的向量 然后你
add on other vectors, you know,
加上其他的向量
plus ... plus the other
vectors, which is why
这就是为什么
overall, this thing
总体而言
over here, that whole
在这里 这整个量
quantity, that delta is
δ 就是一个向量
just some vector, and concretely, the
具体而言
3 elements of delta correspond
对应这三个 δ 的元素
if n2, the 3 elements
如果n等于2
of delta correspond exactly to
δ 的三个元素一一对应
this thing to the second
这个
thing and this third
第二个 以及这第三个
thing, which is why
式子 这就是为什么
when you update theta, according to
当您更新 θ 值时 根据
theta minus alpha delta,
θ - αθ 这个式子
we end up having exactly the
我们最终能得到完全符合最上方更新规则的
same simultaneous updates as the
同步更新
update rules that we have on top.
So, I know that there
我知道
was a lot that happened on
幻灯片上的内容很多
the slides, but again, feel
但是再次重申
free to pause the video and
请随时暂停视频
I either encourage you to
我也鼓励你
step through the difference. If
一步步对比这两者的差异
you're unsure of what just happen,
如果你不清楚刚才的内容
I encourage you to step through
我希望你能一步一步读幻灯片的内容
the slide to make sure you
以确保你理解
understand why is it
为什么这个式子
that this update here with
用 δ 的这个定理
this definition of delta, right?
定义的 好吗 ?
Why is it that that equal
以及它为什么
to this update on top and
和最上面的更新方式是等价的
it's still not clear when insight is
为什么是这样子的
that, you know, this thing over here.
你知道 就是这里的式子
That's exactly the vector
这就是向量 x
x and so, we're
而我们只是用了
just taking, you know, all
你知道
3 of these computations and compressing
这三个计算式并且压缩
them into one step
成一个步骤
with the this vector delta,
用这个向量 δ
which is why we can come
这就是为什么我们能够
up with a vectorized implementation of
矢量化地实现
this step of linear regression this way.
线性回归
So I hope this
所以 我希望
step makes sense, and do
步骤是有逻辑的
look at the video and make
请务必看视频 并且保证
sure and see if you can understand it.
你确实能理解它
In case you don't understand The
万一你是在不能理解
equivalence of this math if
它们数学上等价的原因
you implement this, this turns
你就直接实现这个算法
out to be the right answer anyway,
算是能得到正确答案的
so even if you didn't
所以即使你没有
quite understand the equivalence, if you just implement it this way,
完全理解为何是等价的 如果只是实现这种算法
you'll be able to get linear regressions to work.
你仍然实现线性回归算法
So, if you're able to
所以如果你能
figure out why these 2 steps
弄清楚为什么这两个步骤是等价的
are equivalent then hopefully that
那我希望你可以对
would give you a better understanding of vectorization
向量化有一个更好的理解
as well, and finally,
以及 最后
if you're implementing linear
如果你在实现线性回归的时候
regression using more than one or two features.
使用一个或两个以上的特征量
So, sometimes we use linear
有时我们使用
regression with tens or hundreds
几十或几百个特征量
thousands of features, but if
来计算线性归回
you use the vectorized implementation
当你使用向量化地实现
of linear regression, usually that
线性回归
will run much faster than if
通常运行速度就会比你以前用
you had say your old
你的 for 循环快的多
for loop that was you
也就是自己
know, updating theta 0 then theta 1 then theta 2 yourself.
写代码更新 θ0 θ1 θ2
So, using a vectorized implementation, you
因此使用向量化实现方式
should be able to get a
你应该是能够得到
much more efficient implementation of linear regression.
一个高效得多的线性回归算法
And when you vectorize later
而当你向量化
algorithms that we'll see in
我们将在之后的课程里面学到的算法
this class is a good
这会是一个很好的技巧
trick whether an octave
无论是对于 Octave 或者
or some of the language, the C++
一些其他的语言 如C++
Java for getting your code to run more efficiently.
Java 来让你的代码运行得更高效 【果壳教育无边界字幕组】翻译：Jaminalia  校对：所罗门捷列夫